# **ERIN TOTH FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

erintoth@gmail.com

**\** 778-928-9463

in erintoth

n erinltoth

Full stack web developer with a passion for creative problem solving and learning new things. Strong attention to detail and precision from 7 years of experience as a machinist. A particular interest in building apps that are accessible for a diverse group of users and their specific needs. A lifelong enthusiasm for technology and coding and a diverse range of knowledge and experience from 10+ years in the wine industry.

### Skills

#### **LANGUAGES**

**Javascript** 

Ruby

Python

HTML

CSS

#### FRAMEWORK, LIBRARIES, AND **ENVIRONMENTS**

NodeJS

ReactJS

Rails

Ajax

**Express** 

Knex

**EJS** 

**jQuery** 

**Bootstrap** 

Jest

#### SYSTEMS, CMS & DATABASES

MongoDB

SQL

PostgreSQL

Airtable

#### OTHER TOOLS & ENVIRONMENTS

**Amazon Web Services** 

Docker

## **Projects**

Feb. 2019 Jungle Rails

A mini e-commerce application where users can browse for products (and see if they have a quantity available to buy), add products to their cart, and order via Stripe. Users can register and login and receive a detailed e-mail notification after their order is received. Built using Ruby on Rails, Postgres/Active Record, and HTML/CSS/SASS.

Chatty

A real-time chat app that allows users to send and receive notifications and messages, change their usernames, and view the number of online users live via use of websockets. Built using React, NodeJS, Webpack, and Babel.

Schoodle Feb. 2019

Schoodle is a web application allowing users to arrange an event and have their chosen attendees vote on which date/time works for them by being given a randomly generated URL. It is a group midterm project, and I was responsible for the front end (CSS/HTML as well as dynamic rendering of data), and for the database migrations.

Tweeter

Tweeter is a single page Twitter-clone application built with HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery, and AJAX on the client-side and NodeJS, Express, and MongoDB on the server side.

# **Employment**

Finn Al

Vancouver, BC

Software Engineer Intern

Apr. 2019 to Aug. 2019

- Implemented bug-fixes and features for AI chat bots in an Agile environment using a Jira ticketing system.
- · Worked with product owners to ensure customers in the financial services industry received a product that met or exceeded expectations.
- Implemented and ran unit tests with Jest and smoke/regression tests with TestRails.
- Worked daily with languages/tools/environments including JavaScript, ReactJS, Docker, AWS, Spinnaker, Jenkins

### LT Custom Machining

Richmond, BC

CNC Machinist/Shop Supervisor

Mar. 2011 to Ian. 2019

- Attention to precision and tolerances as small as 0.0001".
- Responsible for debugging CNC machine programs during setups.
- Responsible for precise replication of a product from a schematic or verbal description.

## Self-Employed

Vancouver BC

Wine Consultant/Educator

2008 to Current

- Responsible for teaching wine tasting and apprecation classes to groups ranging from 10 - 100 people.
- Self-driven to create curriculum and keep it updated.

## **Education**

Lighthouse Labs

lan, 2019 to Mar, 2019

Web Development Program

Wine & Spirits Education Trust DipWSET - in progress

2013 to 2015

International Sommelier Guild Certified Sommelier

2006 to 2007